Gautham Arasu

thi.gautham@outlook.com | (469) 432-5281 | linkedin.com/in/th-gautham

ABOUT ME

Professional Interests

Data science, machine learning research, deep learning, statistics and data visualization.

Technical Skills

Python (TensorFlow, Scikit-Learn, Pandas, Numpy, Scipy etc.), RStudio, Jupyter Notebook, MATLAB, git and others. Experienced in data visualization libraries such as ggplot2, pyplot, seaborn and others. Engineering modelling and simulations in CATIA V5, ANSYS, IcePak and others. Familiar with AWS, Talend and Salesforce. Experienced in Agile, Functional data analysis and Process design and development.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

PUBLICIS SAPIENT, Global Project Delivery

Associate Technology

San Francisco, CA (Jan 2020 – Present)

- * Develop data-driven insights to identify process design improvements; collaborate with stakeholders to operationalize opportunities for scaling development and develop predictive models to inform business decisions to senior management.
- Wrangle data from multiple sources (open data orgs and legacy government data systems) using Python and R to develop KPI's and use cases which leveraged to setup data governance and data cleansing process utilizing ETL tool such as Talend.
- Built a new approach to commercial valuation, where assessment increased from 9.1% to as high as 14.7% in June 2020.
- Successfully lead team of 4 directs and managed numerous time critical project deliveries on time.

ASTA CRS Inc, Consultant

San Francisco, CA (Jan 2019 – Jan2020)

- Served as the Functional Lead to Project Delivery Team with the responsibility of business process ownership for solution implementation and collaborating multi-competency teams of data engineers, solution architects and business analysts.
- Incorporate data analysis to augment user decisions and process design improvements.
- * A focus on educating project stakeholders and legacy system SME's into Agile methodology and bringing about Digital Business Transformation in Public Sector.

EMNSPC LAB, Graduate Research Assistant,

Arlington, TX (Jun 2016 - Nov 2018)

Amazon, Product Analyst

Bangalore, IN (Dec 2015- May 2016)

EDUCATION

Master of Science, Mechanical Engineering University of Texas at Arlington Bachelor of Science, Mechanical Engineering Visvesvaraya Technological University Arlington, TX (May 2018)

Bangalore, IN (July 2015)

PERSONAL ACCOMPLISHMENTS & PROJECTS

"Object detection in commercial planning documents for Valuation assessment" – Implemented a CNN feature segmentation POC on building plans to the Deputy Assessor Office as part of Public Sector DBT strategy. San Francisco, CA (June 2020)

"Sales Insight on residential and commercial property" – Built a valuation assessment model leveraging predictive analysis and presented solution to Public sector clients. San Francisco, CA (Apr 2020)

<u>Certified ScrumMaster (CSM)</u>, Scrum Alliance.

Mountain View, CA (Jan 2020)

"Outstanding Teamwork & Publics Service Award" – Global Project Delivery Team, Assessor Property Assessment System Team. San Francisco, CA (Dec 2019)

G.Thirunavakkarasu and et all, "Air flow pattern and path flow simulation of airborne particulate contaminants in Cold aisle containment high-density data center using airside economization"; DOI: 10.1115/IPACK2018-8436;

San Francisco, CA (Aug 2018)